▍2026 美网 女单第一轮
郑钦文 4-6 6-3 6-1 柳托娃 · 赛后场上采访
Qinwen, congratulations.
钦文 恭喜你
First of all,
首先
it is your first Grand Slam main draw win
这是你久违的大满贯正赛胜利
in a little
隔了好一阵子了
while, and you looked incredible doing it.
而且你今天打得非常漂亮
What was the key,
关键是什么
particularly after that first set?
尤其是在丢掉第一盘之后？
Well, first of all, I want
首先 我想
to say congratulation first to the opponent
先恭喜我的对手
because she's only 16 years old,
因为她才 16 岁
very young junior,
还是个很年轻的青少年球员
and she play incredible tennis, fights a lot.
她打得非常出色 也很能拼
It was not easy for me,
这场球对我来说不容易
but first congratulation to her.
但首先还是要恭喜她
And second I mean my body wasn't
第二 我的身体状态
in the best shape
并不在最好的时候
because I was a bit sick few days ago
因为几天前我有点生病
and it was tough for me
有那么一段时间
to keep the consistent in one moment.
我很难保持稳定
I was feeling a bit dizzy on court
在场上我觉得有点头晕
but I just say today what what I
但我告诉自己 今天
can do is only to fight
我能做的只有拼
and let's see what's happen.
然后看看会发生什么
I'm so happy to get this match cuz it
能赢下这场球我太开心了
was really tough for me physically
因为这场球在身体上
and mentally like you say it
和心理上都很难 正如你所说
was my first Grand Slam main draw win
这是我一年多来
more than a year that was means
第一场大满贯正赛胜利
a lot to me and I want to say thank you
这对我意义重大 我想说声谢谢
for all the crowd who come
谢谢今天到场
to support me today I I love you guys
支持我的所有观众 我爱你们
and I just wish I can keep fighting
我只希望自己能一直拼下去
and let's go.
加油
Yeah, it's it is hard
是啊 有时候真的很难分清
to tell whether you are playing in New York
你到底是在纽约打球
or playing in China at times.
还是在中国打球
The amount of love you have here,
这里对你的这份喜爱
the support you feel, especially
你感受到的支持 尤其是
as you're coming back from an injury,
在你从伤病里回来
trying to get back to the top of your game
想重新回到最好状态的时候
has to be special to have moments like
有这样的时刻一定很特别
this and be reminded why you do this.
也提醒着你为什么要打球
Well, yes.
是的
It always special for me
回到纽约
to come back here in New York cuz
对我来说永远都很特别
it's the first time I make quarterfinal is here
我第一次打进大满贯 1/4 决赛
in US Open and I just love to play here.
就是在美网 我很爱在这里打球
Love the passion and everybody brings
我喜欢这里的热情
on the stadium for play tennis.
喜欢大家带到球场上的一切
Once again,
再说一次
thank you everyone really cuz really means
真的谢谢每一个人
a lot this first round but I'm
这场首轮对我意义重大
so happy today to win this match.
今天能赢下来我很开心
One more quick thing.
最后再问一个
I mean, you came through qualifiers.
我是说 你是从资格赛打上来的
You've played a lot
这几天你已经
of tennis the last few days.
打了很多场球
Now you get a day off at least.
现在至少能休息一天
What does Qinwen do in New York
钦文在纽约有一天空闲的时候
when you have a day off?
都会做些什么？
If you're not playing tennis,
如果不打球
what do you enjoy doing around here?
你喜欢在这儿做点什么？
Well, actually when I finished the last round
其实打完资格赛最后一轮
of qualies, I got two days luckily and I've
我幸运地有两天空闲
been visit the city and went for a really light
我去逛了逛这座城市
shopping just few really a few clothes.
还很轻松地买了点衣服
I think all
我想所有
the girl knows what mean few clothes.
女生都懂 一点衣服是什么意思
Yeah, but honestly, one day there's nothing.
不过说实话 一天根本不够
We need to keep going on practice
我们还得继续训练
and, you know, ready for next match.
为下一场做好准备
Yeah.
是的
Well, we're so glad you're sticking around.
我们很高兴你还留在这儿